In this video, we show an example of how you can use the printf function to print
在这个视频中 我们举例介绍如何用printf函数来
output to the terminal.
把我们的结果输出打印到终端
We have our usual frame for main as well as a box for output.
我们可以看到常用的main框架 和一个用于代表输出的框
And the execution arrow is at the start of main.
箭头指在main的开头
We begin by declaring and initializing a to 42.
我们先创建一个变量，并赋值42
Then we reach a printf call.
接下来 我们运行printf语句
We're going to print the string Hello World.
把字符串‘Hello World‘打印到终端
It'll just print this string directly, there are no formats specifies at all.
它会直接打印这个字符串 没有任何其他指定格式
So our output is Hello world.
我们的输出就是“Hello World“（你好世界）
The next printf call with print the string a.
接下来的printf语句将打印字符串“a“
Note that this prints the literal letter a since it is enclosed in
注意这行代码会直接打印出字母a 因为字母a
quotation marks and is therefore a string literal.
在引号的里面 它被当作一个字符串文本
This has nothing with the variable a.
这和我们之前看到的变量a没有联系
So our output is a.
因此 我们的输出是a
And we return 0 and exit main.
接下来的函数返回数值0 并退出main（）
What would you do if you wanted to instead print the value of the variable a?
假设你想打印变量a所代表的数值 该怎么做呢？
The f in printf stands for formatted, and
printf中的“f“代表”formatted“（格式化的）
there are several format specifiers you can use to format your output.
C语言中有一些格式指定符 可用于格式化输出
In this example, first we declare and initialize integers a to 42 and b to 7.
在这个例子中 我们先创建和初始化整数a和b 分别对应42和7
Then we reach a printf call with a format specifier.
接下来我们运行一个带有格式说明符的printf语句
In this case, %d.
在这个例子中 是%d
%d formats integers as decimal numbers.
%d将整数格式转化为十进制数字
And you'll learn later about other format specifiers.
关于其他格式指定符号的知识我们稍后会学习到
%d means printf will look at the corresponding argument to see what
%d意味着printf语句会检查它对应的引数 来判断
integer format is a decimal number.
哪些整数需要被转化成十进制的格式
In this case, it is given variable a.
在我们的例子中 引数是我们的变量a
So it prints the decimal representation
因此 运行这个语句会于%d在字符串的位置
of the number 42 in the location in the string where the %d is.
打印出数字42的十进制格式
The next call to printf has two %ds.
接下来运行的代码中含有两个%d符号
The first refers to b, the next argument after the string which is 7, and
第一个指向b 是字符串后面的第一个变量 代表数字7
the second of these refers to a + b, which is evaluated like any other expression.
其中第二个指向a+b 像任何其他表达式一样运行计算
So it's 42 + 7 which is 49.
所以运算42+7 结果是49
So the output is b is 7 and a + b is 49.
因此，我们的输出b是7  a+b是49
We return 0 and exit main.
在最后 我们返回数值0 然后退出main环境
Another important thing to know about printf is escape sequences.
另一个有关printf的重点是转义序列
An escape sequence begins with a backslash.
转义序列以一个反斜杠 \ 开始
The most common one is \n which means new line.
最常见的一个是 \n  代表新的一行
This printf call has two \ns.
现在看到的printf语句有两个 \n
So you should print two new lines after Hello World.
所以 运行时会在“Hello World”之后打印两行空行
This statement declares and initializes b to 7.
现在看到的语句创建一个变量b 并初始化数值为7
This printf call has a \t in it which means a tab, is useful for
此printf语句中有一个 \t  意思是tab键（选项卡键）
lining up output.
用来整齐排列输出
The output is, my answer is tab 7, we return in exit main.
我们的输出是，“My answer is:  7"  然后返回0并退出main环境
This introduction has shown you a few uses of the printf function and
在本次简介中我们讲解了printf函数的一些用法
you'll see more later in the course.
你会在我们接下来的课程中更加深入地学习